smartrecruiters.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | SmartRecruiters

**Last revised: June 08, 2018**

For SmartRecruiters and its affiliates ( **“SmartRecruiters”** ), protecting your personal information ( **“Personal Information” or “Personal Data”** as defined below)  is our priority. 

We have prepared this privacy policy ( **“Privacy Policy”** ) to describe to you (“you” or the “candidate”) our practices regarding the Personal Information we collect from you as candidate (of our website, located at smartrecruiters.com, our mobile application ( **“Application(s)”** ), and our widgets (collectively, the **“Site”** ) and all online services of SmartRecruiters Inc. and its affiliates ( **“Services”** ). 

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to SmartRecruiters include smartrecruiters.com, SmartRecruiters, Inc. and its affiliates. 

We respect each individual’s right to personal privacy. We will collect and use information we receive directly from you through our website only in the ways disclosed in this Privacy Policy. Information provided to SmartRecruiters by our customers is collected by those customers under their own privacy policies. This policy does not apply to practices that SmartRecruiters does not own or control, or to individuals that SmartRecruiters does not employ or manage. By using smartrecruiters.com, you agree to the data practices described in this statement and you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You can withdraw your consent at any time. Learn more here.

**SmartRecruiters, Inc. adheres to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth below. For more details,click here.**

### What is the purpose of collecting your Personal Information? 

  * Help our customers (“Customers”) find their next hires : when you apply, our customer (the recruiter or hiring manager) can consider you for any job opportunities they have and can use any SmartRecruiters tools to track, manage and make a decision. 
  * Help you manage your job applications : when you apply, you have access to a Candidate Portal, where you can find your profile information and applications information. You can receive jobs suggestions. 

SmartRecruiters is not a headhunting company, we only provide a talent acquisition technology and SaaS services to our Customers.

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by SmartRecruiters. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the services, to maintain and the improve quality of the services, and to provide general statistics regarding use of [smartrecruiters.com](https://smartrecruiters.com/).

SmartRecruiters encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites to which you choose to link from smartrecruiters.com so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. SmartRecruiters is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of [smartrecruiters.com](https://www.smartrecruiters.com/).

### How your data will be used?

SmartRecruiters collects your Personal Information to operate its website and deliver the Services you have requested as set forth above. SmartRecruiters may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current Services or of potential new services that may be offered.

SmartRecruiters does not sell, rent or lease the collected Personal Information and its customer lists to third parties. For SmartRecruiters Hiring Success conferences, SmartRecruiters shall process conference registrants personal data that is necessary to ensure the success of the Hiring Success conference. All conference registrants agree that their information will be shared with conference sponsors ([Americas](https://www.smartrecruiters.com/hiring-success/americas/sponsors/) | [Europe](https://www.smartrecruiters.com/hiring-success/europe/sponsors/)). All conference sponsors agree to the terms and conditions of the data usage restrictions per the General Data Protection Regulation and all applicable data protection laws.

SmartRecruiters may share usage data with trusted partners to help to perform usage statistical analysis, customer support and technical operations and provide data hosting services. All such third parties are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

SmartRecruiters may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within SmartRecruiters, in order to improve your user experience.

SmartRecruiters may use the Personal Data to improve and develop its website, its services and products to the extent this is necessary for its legitimate interests. 

Our Customer may opt in to use features that assist them in the recruitment process through automated means. For you as a candidate, it means that your application is processed and analyzed to identify relevant aspects from your work history such as previous positions and employers, education history, demonstrated skills, and duration of work. These aspects are then compared against the job published by our Customer to indicate how your application corresponds with the requirements outlined in the job listing. 

These findings help our Customer highlight existing information in your application. The automated capabilities are used to facilitate the recruitment process, however, any conclusive hiring decisions are ultimately at the Customer’s discretion.

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework & Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

SmartRecruiters, Inc. adheres the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Data from European Union member countries and Switzerland (<https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome>) to the United States . If there is any conflict between the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. 

SmartRecruiters, Inc. is committed to subjecting all Personal Data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland in compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework ([https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)).

SmartRecruiters, Inc. shall ensure that (i) Personal Data is handled, processed, transferred and stored in accordance with relevant Privacy Shield Principles and EU data protection laws, and (ii) adequate safeguards and procedures providing protection to personal data are in place.

**Inquiries – Contact under Privacy Shield**

The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over SmartRecruiters, Inc. compliance with the Privacy Shield. 

SmartRecruiters, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, SmartRecruiters, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your Personal Information.

Individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact SmartRecruiters at: ** **. SmartRecruiters will respond within 45 days.

In case of unresolved privacy or data use concern, SmartRecruiters, Inc. commits to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner, as applicable and comply with the advice given by the panel and/or Commissioner, as applicable with regard to data transferred from the EU and/or Switzerland, as applicable. Such resolution process is at no cost to the complaining individual.

Under certain conditions explained at [ https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), a binding arbitration option before a Privacy Shield Panel may be available to you.

### Onward transfers

SmartRecruiters adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of Personal Data from the EU or Switzerland and complies with the EU data protection laws.

SmartRecruiters uses a limited number of third-party providers in US and in Europe to provide data hosting services (Amazon Web Services) and to help to perform usage statistical analysis, customer support and technical operations. 

SmartRecruiters shall remain responsible in case of onward transfers to third parties. SmartRecruiters shares the Personal Information with these third-party providers to support SmartRecruiters’ Services only. Any other use of the Personal Data by third-party providers is prohibited. 

All third-party providers receiving Personal Data from the European Union and/or Switzerland agree to (i) process the Personal Data only to the extent required by SmartRecruiters’ Services and in accordance with SmartRecruiters’ instructions and (ii) comply with the data protection laws for transfer and processing of personal data and (iii) provide adequate technical and organization measures to protect the Personal Information.

To this end, we use the European Standard Contract clauses (<https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>) with our sub processors in order to guarantee the privacy and the security of your Personal Information. 

### How can you access to your Personal Information?

SmartRecruiters acknowledges that individuals have a right to access to, correct, amend and delete their Personal Information. Because SmartRecruiters is the data processor of the Personal Information and collects Personal Information under the instructions of its Customers, SmartRecruiters shall follow its Customers’ instructions. Therefore, SmartRecruiters encourages the individuals to contact these Customers. This can be done by replying to the last email that was sent via the SmartRecruiters system. 

### Use of Cookies

SmartRecruiters may use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize SmartRecruiters pages, or register with SmartRecruiters site or services, a cookie helps SmartRecruiters to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your Personal Data, such as Login information. When you return to www.smartrecruiters.com, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the SmartRecruiters features that You customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies.

### Security and retention of your Personal Information

SmartRecruiters is ISO 27001 certified. 

SmartRecruiters uses industry-standard technologies when transferring and receiving data exchanged between SmartRecruiters and third parties to help ensure its security. SmartRecruiters’ website has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of information.

Personal Information are stored on servers maintained by Amazon Web Services and subject to their security safeguards which are continuously audited, with certifications from accreditation bodies across geographies and verticals. You can read more about Amazon Web Services’ security and compliance at <https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/>.

SmartRecruiters will retain your Personal Information for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. 

### Children Under Thirteen

SmartRecruiters does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use [smartrecruiters.com](https://www.smartrecruiters.com/). If a child under 13 submits Personal Information to Company and we learn that the Personal Information is the information of a child under 13, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible. If you believe that we might have any Personal Information from a child under 13, please contact us at  .

### Opt-Out & Unsubscribe

We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Users may opt-out of receiving any or all communications from SmartRecruiters by following the “unsubscribe” link on communication received from SmartRecruiters or otherwise by contacting us at:

**– Email: **

### How to contact us

SmartRecruiters may disclose your Personal Information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on SmartRecruiters or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of SmartRecruiters; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of SmartRecruiters, or the public.

If you have any inquiries or complaints regarding the processing of your data, you should first contact SmartRecruiters at:  . SmartRecruiters will respond in a timely manner.

In case of unresolved privacy or data use concern, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your data protection supervisory authority.
